### **ALFREDO CRISTOFORETTI**

Address: Via Brugo, 5 - 10041 Carignano (To) - Italy

Mobile: +39.335.1852963

E-mail: alfredo.cristoforetti@gmail.com

### **Personal Profile**

A successful experience as Marketing, Business Development and Sales Lead in the IT space with specific reference to Manufacturing and Retail sector. Proven ability to work with high level international customers and identify new business opportunity. Excellent team player skills and envisioning attitude. Like to win business with a solution selling approach.

Typically working with the EMEA subsidiaries of Multinational Corporations, have often played a role in influencing business units to define new products lines addressing specific customer requirements and market opportunities.

## **Professional Experiences**

#### 2005 - 2010 MICROSOFT

Leading IT Corporation; (Nasdq: MSFT) 90.000 Employees, 62 B USD Revenue

#### EMEA Marketing Director Manufacturing and Retail

Responsible for Business Development, Marketing and Partner Marketing the EMEA Region

- Manage and develop partner relationship with the area of responsibility
- Achieving targets with respect to Lead Generation and Opportunity Optimization in the Enterprise customer Segments
- Develop campaigns with key partners like Accenture, Avanade, Dassault Systemes, Siemens UGS, Siemens MES, Rockwell Software, Invensys

#### Principal Achievementes:

- > Designed and Executed many high visibility initiatives with strong impact and outcome
- Created Pan-European Roadshow with Global and Local Microsoft solution partners achieving 2.5 M Euro sponsorship from Partners and Media Agencies, generating more than 100 Business Opportunities
- ➤ Developed 'Empowering Excellence Roadshow' to generate CRM opportunities in the Manufacturing and Retail space with successful deployment and 30 new opportunities identified in Italy, Spain, France, Sweden, Denmark Finland, Austria and Turkey

#### 1991 – 2005 ROCKWELL INTERNATIONAL

Lead in Industrial automation solutions; (NYSE: ROK) 20.000 Employee, 5 B USD Revenue

# 2001 – 2005 European Business Manager – MES Solutions (ROCKWELL SOFTWARE)

- Responsible for Rockwell's Manufacturing Execution Systems and Plant Intelligence Offering for the EMEA area with priority focus on Global accounts like Kraft, Nestle, Fiat, Heineken
- Total responsibility on Sales, Business Development and Marketing leading a Pan-European team

### **Principal Achievementes:**

- ➤ Launched new product line of Plant Floor Operations & Intelligence achieving a CAGR of 25% for 3 years in a row
- Developed Business with key client cooperating to major with customers like Kraft, Pirelli Tyres, Cadbury, Continental, Fiat Group
- Redefined Solution Offering, creating trial package in cooperation with various Business Units and Service department obtaining great customer feedbach which lead to the above mentioned growth

# 1996 – 2001 *EMEA Marketing Director* (ROCKWELL SOFTWARE)

 Lead EMEA Marketing and Business Development for Rockwell Software. Responsibility for planning, Execution and pipeline of the overall software Business, Managing team of incountry Marketing Managers

### **Principal Achievementes:**

- Delivered strong pipeline thru major marketing campaigns
- Managed Partner relationship and Microsoft Alliance with nomination of 'Partner of the Year in FY 2000

## 1991 – 1996 Marketing Manager Automation Systems (ROCKWELL AUTOMATION)

- Initially Product Manager for the automation line of business
- From 1993 responsibility for overall Marketing and Communication Activities for the Italian region (Including Greece, Turkey and Israel)

## Other experiences

## Actually PRAMAC

Leading European Company in Renewable Energy Sector ( <a href="www.pramac.com">www.pramac.com</a> )

**Consulting activity** targeted at development integrated projects on Renewable energy and energy savingt with specific focus on strategy definition and key customer engagement.

### **Education and training**

**1984 – 1989** B.Sc. – Engineering (110/110 magna cum laude)

University of Pavia - Ghisleri College

**1990** Ricercatore

Master in Applied Technology - Politecnico of Milan

### **Personal details**

Date of Birth: Feb 15th 1964

Marital Status: Married, Two Children

Languages: Italian (mother tongue); English (Good Proficiency); French (Basic)

I hereby authorize the use of my personal information pursuant to Italian Legis. Decree 196/2003